Guide to the Patrick Daughton Papers AIA.055
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II. Irish Republican Clubs, 1969-1988
  - Chicago, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Colorado, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - East Bay, San Francisco: Meeting Notes, 1974-1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Education Program, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Gerry Doherty / Ray Strain (Sonoma), 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Helena Moloney Club (Berkeley), 1975-1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - James Connolly Club (Berkeley), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - James Connolly Club (Berkeley): Irish Republican News Service, 1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - John McCann (San Jose), 1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Letterhead - various, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Liam Mellows Club (Minneapolis/St. Paul), 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Liam Mellows Club (San Francisco), 1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Literature, 1976-1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles: Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - New Mexico / Arizona, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - New York Office: Albany I, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New York Office: Albany II, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - New York Office: Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - North American Clubs: Conventions, Agenda, Resolutions, Amendments, 1973-1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - North American Clubs: Correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - North American Clubs: Literature Lists (National Office), 1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - North American Clubs: National Executive Committee - New York I, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - North American Clubs: National Executive Committee - New York II, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - North American Clubs: National Material I, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - North American Clubs: National Material II, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - North American Clubs: Pamphlets and Publications, 1975-1976, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - North American Clubs: Resolution Book (Support International Freedom Efforts), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Northern California Clubs: Easter Commemoration Breakfast, 1981-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Northern California Clubs: Statements, Press Releases, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Oregon - Inquiries, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Other Clubs: United States, Canada, Australia, New Zealand, 1977-1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Patrick Sheils Club (Washington, DC), 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Press Releases, 1974-1977 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Press Releases, 1975-1981 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Publications: Drithleog (USA/CANADA), 1972-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Publications: Internal Newsletter, 1972-1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Irish Worker No. 6-8. 11-32, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Publications: United Ireland Solidarity Newsletter, 1974-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Publications: United Ireland Solidarity Newsletter: Newsletter mockups, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Publications: United Ireland Solidarity Newsletter: Newsletter mockups, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Publications: United Ireland Solidarity Newsletter: Newsletter mockups; photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - San Jose: Education Outline I, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - San Jose: Education Outline II, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party Literature, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Six County Executive (Belfast), 197_ (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, Solidarity Statements, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - United States Clubs, 1976-1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Series III. Publications, 1881-1998
  This series contains partial runs of several publications organized alphabetically. Also included are newspaper clippings organized by subject and articles and partial issues from historical newspapers.
  - An Eochair: Republican Bulletin, Long Kesh, 1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Ballymurphy News (Republican Clubs Newsletter):Organ of Orr-Gray Rep Club. Clarke-Larkin Rep Club, Casement Rep. Club, Tracey Rep Club, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Breton News, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Burca, Mairin de "Revolutionary" (Pamphlet), circa 1972-1976 (Box Shared Tamiment 157, Folder 15)
  - Celtic League / Celtic News, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Civil Rights: Newsbulletin of Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association (NICRA), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights: Fortnightly Journal of the Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association (NICRA), 1973 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Clor Na Saoirse: Official Newspaper of the Irish American Community, Feb 25, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Congress '86, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Eolas (Dublin), 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - The Felon's Book, 1982 (Box Shared Tamiment 157, Folder 13)
  - The Freeman's Journal; Oct 26 and Oct 30 issues, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - The Gaelic American (New York) Issues: Dec 29, 1906; Aug 18,1906; Dec 21, 1907 (2 issues); Apr 6, 1907; Sep 26, 1908; Jul 17, 1909; Oct 29, 1910; Nov 12, 1910; Jun 10, 1910; Sep 30, 1911; Jun 17, 1911; Nov 15, 1911; Jun 10, 1911; Mar 30, 1912; Mar 14, 1914; Nov 21, 1914; Apr 13, 1914; Mar 6, 1915 (2 issues);Aug 21, 1915; Jul 10, 1915; Jul 17, 1915, 1906-1915 (Box 13)
  - Guth an Phobail (Public Voice): The Community for Justice, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Ireland (International Magazine of Sinn Fein the Workers' Party), 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Ireland Today: Two Issues: 1980; Vol. 1, No. 1 Mar/Apr, 1980-1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Irish American Information Service, 1992-1998 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Irish American Unity Conference National Newsletter (Washington DC), 1992-1998 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Irish American Unity Conference Newsletter (California Chapter), 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Irish American Voice, Vol. 5, Nos. 2, 3, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Irish Democrat: Organ of the Connolly Association (London) (2 issues: Sep 1989, Nov 1980), 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Irish Newsline: Newsletter of the Irish American Unity Conference (San Antonio, TX), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Irish Northern Aid Bulletin (INAC): "Newsletter of the West Coast Irish Northern Aid Units", 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Irish Northern Aid Bulletin (INAC): Newsletter of the West Coast, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Irish Northern Aid Bulletin (INAC): Newsletter of the West Coast, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee Newsletter (INAC) (San Francisco), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Irish Northern Aid News: "Newsletter of the West Coast Irish Northern Aid Units", May 1993-Sep 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Irish Northern Aid Nuacht (San Francisco), 1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Irish People: The Voice of Irish Republicanism in America (New York) Vol. 17, No. 15, May 5, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Irish Republican Clubs Newsletter No. 1-5, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Irish World (New York), Sep 6, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The Irish World (formerly The Gaelic American) Two Issues: Feb, 18, 1978, May 26, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Leader (San Francisco) Issues: Oct 29, 1910; Oct 23, 1920, 1910-1920 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - The New International (New York) 2 issues: Mar 1947, Jan 1948, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Northern Ireland Report (Lowell, MA), 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Nuacht Naisunta, 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Nuacht Naisunta, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Nuacht Sheirbhis Sinn Fein (Weekly News Service) I, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Nuacht Sheirbhis Sinn Fein (Weekly News Service) II, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - People's News Service (London), 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - People's World (Berkeley, CA)(Various Clippings), 1975-1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Scots Independent (Stirling) Nov 1973, Feb 1974 issues, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Teioric: Theoretical and Discussion Journal of Sinn Fein The Workers Party, 1976-1980, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - United Ireland Newsletter (Albany, NY) I, 1976-1978, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - United Ireland Newsletter (Albany, NY) II, 1976-1978, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - United Ireland Solidarity Newsletter (Oakland, CA), 1974-1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - United Irishman (New York) Issues: Jan 26, 1907; Jul 3, 1909, 1907-1909 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - United Irishman: Newspaper of Sinn Fein the Workers Party (2 issues, Jan, Mar), 1980 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - World Affairs Newsletter (Dublin), 1977 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Y Faner Goch: For a Welsh Socialist Republic, circa 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Historical Newspaper Clippings/Fragments: The Gaelic American, 1911, The Ladies Home Journal (Philadelphia), 1911, National Hibernian, 1911, other fragments - the Leader, 1909-1914 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Individual Issues: The Captive Voice, Autumn 1989; Comment Fortnightly, Jun 1977; IRIS, Aug 1989; Making Sense, Summer 1988; Newsfront International, July 1981; Sinn Fein Speaks, 1980; Unity, Jun 1974; UWC Journal: The Voice of the Ulster Workers Council, Vol. 1, No. 4; Y Fanergoch (Welsh paper) circa 1985, 1974-1989 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Individuals Issues (cartoons): The Graphic, Puck, Punch (oversize box), 1881-1891 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Blanket Protest 1980 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles: British Army in Northern Ireland, 1972-1977 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper Clippings: British Torture in Northern Ireladn, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper Clippings: The Daily Californian, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper Clippings: General, 1975-1986 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Irish - General (Ireland), 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Irish Language (San Francisco Chronicle) (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Mooney, Tom, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Political Conditions / Repressive Legislation, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Protestant Paramilitary Terrorism Confirmed and Credited, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Provisional IRA Terrorism Confirmed and Credited, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Reagan / Queen Protest, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Trade Unions, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles: Women's Peace Movement, Northern Ireland, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Series IV. Posters, 1972-1998, undated
  This series contains over 50 posters. The poster collection came with detailed annotations and notes for many of the items and this information has been preserved in the folder descriptions. The original groupings of posters has been maintained. While not all posters are listed at the item level, item counts are given for each category.
  - Batalion de San Patricio / A Flag to Fly Note: Poster and folder collected in Mexico during the 1993 tour organized by the Irish Mexican Association (3 items). The IMA was organized by Pat Goggins who was also the organizer of the Irish Forum. Prominent members included Chris Matthews of the IRC in Santa Cruz, and Marco Gonzalez, who lead a group of Mexican Army re-enacters. In addition to marching in both the St. Patrick's Day Parade and the Cinco de Mayo Parade in San Francisco, IMA lead a tour to Mexico to watch and participate in San Patricio memorials and to the California border to investigate conditions for illegal immigrants trying to cross the border. Mark Day, a documentary film maker in San Diego (and former Franciscan priest) was involved at the San Diego end. Mark had written a screenplay about the San Patricios and also produced a short documentary about them. Chris Matthews had written a play about the San Patricios called "A Flag to Fly" that was produced in Santa Cruz and Berkeley (and possibly Ireland). Folders about Chris Matthews and IMA are also found in the collection in Series I. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Free Bill Quinn (1 item) Note: This was a poster carried at demonstrations fighting Bill Quinn's extradition to England. Quinn was a San Francisco Irish American who had been recruited to the Provos by Chuck Malone. He was with the Provos for a few years then returned to San Francisco. He was arrested by the FBI on an extradition warrant by the British government and charged with shooting and killing a British policeman in London. He was extradited and served some time in jail. What's interesting about the photo is the graphic. The graphic of the man behind bars was one that the Officials used for Cabhair, their prisoners' aid group (see folder on Cabhair in Series I). It also appears in issues of the United Irishman before the Official IRA declared its ceasefire. There is some irony in the this in that the image was later used by a group supporting a Provisional IRA man., undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Free Ireland Now: Delancey Street Foundation, John Maher (1 item) Note: This generic poster (includes a shamrock in the upper right hand side) wa created by John Maher of the Delancey Street Foundation and distributed at most of the Irish Action Committee events. Maher also distributed them at any other Irish demonstrations he and his people attended. Maher was an early proponent of branding and framing and he wanted to create a generic poster that Irish activists could bring to any event or demonstration – a message that was broad but not controversial, that wouldn't be dated., undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Free the Birmingham Six – The Winchester Three and Judith Ward (6 items) Note: The poster was produced by the Justice Campaign for Irish Prisoners Abroad. This was a small group, lead by a Dubliner who was a graphic artist who designed the poster that was then distributed to support groups in Ireland, England, Canada, Europe, and South America. The poster was designed so that local groups could fill in the location of the demonstration. Also included are individual blown-up photos of the Birmingham Six when they first appeared in court (after the police had extracted their "confessions"). These photos were distributed to marchers to carry at the demonstrations., undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Grand Jury Subpoeana / Ain't it Grand? (2 items) Notes: Two posters produced by the Bay Area Committee to Stop the Grand Jury. These posters were distributed by the Irish Community Defense Committee. Of note is that one of the individuals being grabbed by the throat in one of the cells has an IRA armband. Separate folders for "Grand Jury" and "Irish Committee Defense/Support Committee" in the collection., undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - History in the Making: A Day of New Irish Film and various posters advertising cultural events (12 items) Note: Poster by the Irish Film Society of San Francisco listing a day of new Irish film at the Roxie Theater. Irish Film Society material is also found in Series I. Other posters contain information on festivals, plays, and the Bloomsummer festival sponsored by a short-lived Irish Community Television program. The poster for the Irish Fair at Fort Mason includes a graphic from the cover of program from an Irish Fair in 1894 (crossed Irish and American flags with a shamrock over both of them). John Jones has the original 1894 program in his collection and loaned it so the organizers could use the graphic. One small poster advertises a set of classes/workshops by the New College Irish Studies Program (See also Dan Cassidy Papers, AIA 049)., 1986-1991, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Internment, undated
  - The Irish Hunger Strike Commemoration 1981-1991 (1 item) Note from donor: The commemoration was sponsored by an uneasy coalition of Provo and ISRP/INLA supporters. To say that things were tense would be an understatement. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Irish Republican Club Posters (15 items) This group includes posters from Sinn Fein (Official), later Sinn Fein the Workers Party, and groups or coalitions close to the Officials like the Union of Students of Ireland, Resource Protection Campaign, Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association. Some of these posters were sold at book tables, others were just on display at events, 1972, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Irish Republican Club events: A set of posters announcing events sponsored or cosponsored by local includings: The Only Penetrable Point of a Tyrant is Fear of Death; Support the IRA (with Dick Tracy saying it, a bestselling poster); Bloody Sunday: A Commemoration (advertising a commemoration cosponsored by the IRCs and IAAA); A Spirit Thus Outraged Will Ever Turn and Come Again Demanding Justice (7 items) Note: Some of the posters were created by a group of anarchists who were sympathizers and used to work at the Starry Plough pub in Berkeley. Those posters had a TTG (Tree Toad Graphics) or Potato Underground or Pu logo. The last poster is an interesting case. A few years later the graphic and words showed up on the cover of The Plough, the newsletter of the Official Republican Movement is South Down/South Armagah: http://cedarlounge.wordpress.com/2008/04/29/the-left-archive-the-plough-from-the-official-republican-movement-in-south-downsouth-armagh-c-1977/ Posters and graphics, as well as people, moved back and forth between Ireland and the U.S. In this case, between Berkeley, California and Newry., 1976, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Northern Ireland Civil Rights, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Provo Posters: 20 Years of Death Squads / Disband the mUrDeRers /Victory to the Blanket Men Bloody Sunday / 18th Commemoration – Free the Birmingham Six (3 items) Note: Like the Irish Republican Clubs, Noraid and groups that supported the Provisional Republicans sold posters that were made in Ireland at events in San Francisco., circa 1998, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Stop the British Death Fleet: Irish Action Committee (1 item) Note: The Irish Action Committee was organized by John Maher, of the Delancey Street Foundation and was a coalition group that consisted of members of Irish Northern Aid, the Irish Republican Clubs, and assorted independent activists. The IAC was mainly involved in specific actions was not an ongoing organization. It was involved in demonstrations for the visit to San Francisco by the British Fleet, Prince Charles'svisit to the SF Bay Area, and the Reagan/Thatcher meeting. Series I also contains documentation of these events. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Posters: Patrick Pearse Commemoration, Anne Devlin IRC; "While you're muinchin your organic raisins...Remember you still gotta smash the state!"; Terence MacSwiney, Irish Martyr (1879-1920), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Posters: The Fureys, The Wolfe Toners - muscial events; several homemade posters in support of Bobby Sands and notices of closings on his death; Sinn Fein Workers Party posters, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Series V. Ephemera and NonPrint, 1966-1995, undated
  - 45 record Side A: London's Derry by Blackthorne; Side B: Man from the Daily Mail. The Blackthorn. Derry Label, Republic of Ireland. "Royalties from sale to help fight repression and sectarianism in N.I.", 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 45 record Side A: 1. Monologue, 2. Army of the People The Bridesmen; Side B: 1. Ballad of Tony Hughes, 2. Ballad of Jim McGerrigan. The Bridesmen. Malpad Records, Armagh Records Co. Ltd., 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 45 record: "Rebel Irish Women: Helena Molony, Kathleen Behan, Maud Gonne MacBride" Claddagh Records Ltd., Dublin. Side 1: Helena Moloney, Kathleen Behan, Maud Gonne MacBride; Side 2. Helena Moloney, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bumper Sticker: American Irish Unity Conference, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Banner: "Solidarity with Palestine" Irish Republican Clubs (white fabric), undated (Box 15)
  - Banner: "Peace Work Class Politics" (gold fabric), undated (Box 15)
  - Banner: "England out of Ireland" (white fabric) (Box 15)
  - Banner: Symbol of Plough and Stars (SFWP?) (Blue and gold fabric), undated (Box 15)
  - Banner: "Overthrough [sic] of British Imperialistic Rule. An Independent Irish Socialist Republic. Opposition to all foreign financiers, monopolists, landlords, speculators and their native collaborators. The rights of common people befor the rights of property. Onwership of Ireland for the people of Ireland. (Blue/white fabric), undated (Box 15)
  - Banner: "Defeat British Imperialism" (white fabric), undated (Box 15)
  - Flag: "England out of Ireland Now March 3rd Coalition" from Reagan/Thatcher Demonstration at Golden Gate Park, Mar 3, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Irish Republican Clubs: Postcards (from Anti-war groups in England); sold in San Francisco, California, 1991, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Irish Republican Clubs: Raffle Tickets for various fundraisers, 1974-1995, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Irish Republican Clubs: Signatures of Secretaries (cards), 1973, 1977, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Party (IRSP) San Francisco: Raffle Tickets, 1983, 1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - NORIAD San Francisco: Raffle Tickets, 1998-1995, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Provo: Stamps and Stickers, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, black/white; 4x6, 8x10: Northern Ireland - Derry City. Taken by Ray Strain, IRC member, during the Official/IRSP split, [1974] undated (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
  - Photographs, color, 3x5: Sinn Fein Gardner Place Headquarters and staff. Taken by Ray Strain, IRC member., 1975, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stamps: Friends of the MacBride Principles (check endorsement, address, etc (Anne Devlin Club), undated (Box 16, Folder 11)